<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: announcements | Phil 428]]></title>
  <link href="http://perezcarballo.org/phil428/blog/categories/announcements/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://perezcarballo.org/phil428/"/>
  <updated>2012-02-23T11:25:34-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://perezcarballo.org/phil428/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Alejandro Pérez Carballo]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Readings for the week of 2/6]]></title>
    <link href="http://perezcarballo.org/phil428/blog/2012/02/02/readings-for-the-week-of-2-slash-6/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-02T10:02:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://perezcarballo.org/phil428/blog/2012/02/02/readings-for-the-week-of-2-slash-6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Next week we will continue our discussion of chapters 5 and 6 of Hare&#8217;s <em><a href='http://www.oxfordscholarship.com.libproxy.usc.edu/view/10.1093/0198810776.001.0001/acprof-9780198810773'>The Language of Morals</a></em>, and move on to discuss chapters 7 and 8. After reading chapters 7 and 8, you may want to look at P. T. Geach, <a href='http://www.jstor.org.libproxy.usc.edu/stable/2183506'>&#8216;Ascriptivism&#8217;</a>, <em>Philosophical Review</em>, 69(2), 1960, pp. 221-225.</p>

<p>Remember that your <a href='http://perezcarballo.org/phil428/assignments/#critical'>first assignment</a> is due on Monday.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Attendance]]></title>
    <link href="http://perezcarballo.org/phil428/blog/2012/01/30/attendance/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-30T16:06:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://perezcarballo.org/phil428/blog/2012/01/30/attendance</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As stated in the <a href='http://dl.dropbox.com/u/2015884/phil428.pdf'>syllabus</a>:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>Reading, writing, and engaging with the material in discussion are all important aspects of philosophy. As such, <em>attendance is mandatory</em>, except in the case of a legitimate documented excuse.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Keep in mind that 10% of your grade will be based on attendance and participation.</p>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Next week]]></title>
    <link href="http://perezcarballo.org/phil428/blog/2012/01/25/next-week/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-25T15:29:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://perezcarballo.org/phil428/blog/2012/01/25/next-week</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Next week we will finish our discussion about the Private Language Argument. After that, we will move on to talk about Hare&#8217;s <em>The Language of Morals</em>. I will specify the relevant sections in the next day or two. In the meantime, I wanted to give you some suggestions for how to prepare for our next meeting.</p>
<!-- more -->
<p>Remember that we were considering two different candidates for the conclusion of the Private Language Argument. Wittgenstein is arguing against the possibility of a language in which &#8220;The individual words <span>&#8230;</span> are to refer to what can only be known to the person speaking; to his immediate private sensations&#8221; (&#167;243). But this can be interpreted in one of two ways:</p>

<ol>
<li>Words (or expressions) cannot refer to these &#8216;private sensations&#8217;.</li>

<li>No word can be such that its meaning is exhausted by the &#8216;private sensations&#8217; it refers to.</li>
</ol>

<p>Please think about the following two questions. Your answers to these will form the basis for our discussion next Monday.</p>

<ul>
<li>Can we argue from (1) to the conclusion that <em>there are no</em> private sensations?</li>

<li>What reasons does Wittgenstein provide for thinking that (2) is true? Do they also support the claim that (1) is true?</li>
</ul>

<p>In thinking about these questions, you should grant Wittgenstein the following claim.<sup id='fnref:1'><a href='#fn:1' rel='footnote'>1</a></sup></p>

<blockquote>
<p>For a word to have meaning, there must be publicly available standards to determine when utterances of sentences involving are correct.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Do not hesitate to contact me if you have any questions. And remember that I hold office hours on Mondays from 1-3.</p>
<div class='footnotes'><hr /><ol><li id='fn:1'>
<p>See the section titled &#8216;Wittgenstein on Meaning, Understanding, and Following a Rule&#8217; in Soames, <em>Philosophical Analysis in the Twentieth Century</em>, Vol. 2 for discussion of this thesis in the context of the discussion of the rule-following considerations.</p>
<a href='#fnref:1' rev='footnote'>&#8617;</a></li></ol></div>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
