<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: announcements | Phil 428]]></title>
  <link href="http://perezcarballo.org/phil428/blog/categories/announcements/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://perezcarballo.org/phil428/"/>
  <updated>2012-01-27T12:49:53-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://perezcarballo.org/phil428/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Alejandro Pérez Carballo]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Next week]]></title>
    <link href="http://perezcarballo.org/phil428/blog/2012/01/25/next-week/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-25T15:29:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://perezcarballo.org/phil428/blog/2012/01/25/next-week</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Next week we will finish our discussion about the Private Language Argument. After that, we will move on to talk about Hare's <em>The Language of Morals</em>. I will specify the relevant sections in the next day or two. In the meantime, I wanted to give you some suggestions for how to prepare for our next meeting.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Remember that we were considering two different candidates for the conclusion of the Private Language Argument. Wittgenstein is arguing against the possibility of a language in which "The individual words [...] are to refer to what can only be known to the person speaking; to his immediate private sensations" (&sect;243). But this can be interpreted in one of two ways:</p>

<ol>
<li>Words (or expressions) cannot refer to these 'private sensations'.</li>
<li>No word can be such that its meaning is exhausted by the 'private sensations' it refers to.</li>
</ol>


<p>Please think about the following two questions. Your answers to these will form the basis for our discussion next Monday.</p>

<ul>
<li>Can we argue from (1) to the conclusion that <em>there are no</em> private sensations?</li>
<li>What reasons does Wittgenstein provide for thinking that (2) is true? Do they also support the claim that (1) is true?</li>
</ul>


<p>In thinking about these questions, you should grant Wittgenstein the following claim.</p>

<blockquote><p>For a word to have meaning, there must be publicly available standards to determine when utterances of sentences involving are correct.</p></blockquote>

<p>(See the section titled 'Wittgenstein on Meaning, Understanding, and Following a Rule' in Soames, <em>Philosophical Analysis in the Twentieth Century</em>, Vol. 2 for discussion of this thesis in the context of the discussion of the rule-following considerations.)</p>

<p>Do not hesitate to contact me if you have any questions. And remember that I hold office hours on Mondays from 1-3.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
